Finding Aid for Women of the University Faculty (University of Michigan) records, 1939-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Women of the University Faculty (University of Michigan), records 1939-2003
Women of the University Faculty (University of Michigan).
1 linear foot
87348 Bimu M3 2
Records, 1939-1983, of the Women of the University Faculty. Includes constitution, history, membership rosters, minutes, financial reports, and correspondence.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was received in November 1983 (donor no. 7010 ) Periodic additions have been received.
TThe record group is open without restriction.
Women of the University Faculty began meeting informally in February 1939. At that time the group was known as Faculty Women. Various changes have taken place as the organization became more structured, including changing the name to the present one during the 1940-1941 academic year, and the adoption of a constitution in the fall of 1946. According to the constitution, the purpose of the group is "to promote good fellowship, a community of professional interest, and a closer cooperation among the women of the various faculties."
Most of the records, 1939-1983, of the Women of the University Faculty have been arranged in chronological order by academic year. The first files contain basic information -- such as a history, various revisions of the constitution, publicity, duties of officers, and summaries of activities. There are also files relating to the group's clubroom and the hosting of the Senate and House Club (wives of Michigan legislators) on two occasions. The general files, arranged by academic year, include membership rosters, lists of officers and committee members, minutes, financial reports, and correspondence.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Faculty.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.; College teachers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Women college teachers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Women of the University Faculty (University of Michigan)
- Records
  - Constitution (Box 1)
  - History (Box 1)
  - Hosting of Senate and House Club, 1954 and 1958 (Box 1)
  - House Committee Related to Clubroom, 1946-1952 (Box 1)
  - Obituaries, 1985-2003 (Box 1)
  - Officers' Duties (Box 1)
  - Programming, 1976-2001 (Box 1)
  - Publicity (Box 1)
  - Summaries, 1940-1954 (Box 1)
  - General files, undated and 1939/1940-1992/1993, 48 folders (Box 1)
    (1965/1966 missing)